# — AHSAN ZAIDI ← **FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER**

### **CONTACT**



832-537-2825



zaidiahsan.r@gmail.com



Portfolio



LinkedIn

#### SKILLS

### **Programming Languages**

✓ HTML5, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, NODE.JS SQL, EXPRESS.JS, SEQUELIZE, REACT

#### Databases

MYSQL, NO SQL, MONGO DB, **RELATIONAL DATABASES** 

### Software/Technologies

✓ VS CODE, GITHUB, GITBASH, HEROKU, INSOMNIA, NPM, JSON, JSX, WEB API, SERVER SIDE API, MVP, MVC, ORM, OOP, MS OFFICE, HANDLEBARS, JEST, MONGOOSE, MERN

### **EDUCATION**

### University of Texas

(2022)

FullStack Web Developer Certification

## University of Texas SA

(2016-2021)

Computer Science

#### **PROFILE**

Self-motivated web developer with considerable technical skills in both front and backend development. A quick learner able to play a key role in streamlining existing codebases writing reusable code to encourage efficient workflow. A keen eye for front end development, with a strong desire to improve my existing skillset through experience; Eager and ready to lead into the next step from intern to professional programmer.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Binary Chemist – Web Developer intern

(2021-2022)

At Binary Chemist I was responsible for determining the structure while designing client webpages, which includes developing new user features in reusable blocks of code. Using a variety of markup languages, I was tasked with improving existing codebases; optimizing page load times and maintaining code accuracy through jest testing.

### CVS Pharmacy - Shift Supervisor

(2019-2021)

Managed store operations along with shift records, producing timely reports to keep higher management up-to-date. Documenting transactions on a day to day basis to promote inventory accuracy. Coordinated workflow and maintained employee schedules to improve efficiency while assessing team performances to encourage productivity.

#### **PROJECTS**

(2021-2022)

- TACO APP
- README GENERATOR
- WEATHER DASHBOARD
- **CODE QUIZ**
- NOTE TAKER
- TECH BLOG

- WORK DAY SCHEDULER
- **SNAKE**
- SOCIAL NETWORK API
- E-COMMERCE BACKEND
- **EMPLOYEE TRACKER**
- REACT PORTFOLIO